# Zachary Hervieux-Moore

# **Profile**

PhD candidate researching deep reinforcement learning and its applications. My goal is to expand the Alpha Zero algorithm to a larger class of games and apply it to robotics problems. Broad interest in machine learning and software engineering. When I'm not reading arXiv, I'm reading Hacker News.

## Contact

Phone: (609) 608-0336
Email: zhm@princeton.edu
Website: hervature.com

# **Skills**

# Programming:

C++, Python, Ruby

## Web Development:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL

#### Web Frameworks:

Django, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap

#### Software:

Git, Perforce, Puppet, LaTeX, Tensorflow

#### Languages:

English, French

# **Awards**

- The Gordon B. and Nancy R. Stewart, Jr. Fellowship
- Dean's Scholar x 4
- Nellie & Ralph Jeffery Award in Mathematics x 2
- Edith Whyte Prize in Macroeconomics Theory
- The Annie Bentley Lillie Prize in Calculus
- Queen's Principal's Scholarship
- Governor General's Award

# Education

#### Princeton University, Princeton, NJ

2016-present

- -PhD Candidate in Operations Research and Financial Engineering
- Linear & Nonlinear Optimization
- Statistical Theory and Methods
- Probability Theory
- Advanced Algorithm Design
- Computational Finance in C++
- Convex & Conic Optimization
- Statistical Learning & Nonparametric Estimation
- Stochastic Calculus

# Queen's University, Kingston, ON

2011-2016

- Bachelor of Science Engineering, Mathematics and Engineering, Systems and Robotics Option
- -Bachelor of Arts, Economics

# **Experience**

#### Stratyfy, NYC, NY Data Scientist

Summers 2018, 2019

- —Developed a novel discretisation algorithm that boosted our models' performance to match state of the art techniques.
- -Wrote technical and non technical case studies of our methodology that are used to pitch customers, investors, or published online.
- -Built internal tools written in Python to automate the process of transitioning customers to our machine learning platform.

#### Siemens Healthineers, Princeton, NJ Business Program Intern

Summer 2017

- -Responsible for the formulation and development of the underlying algorithm used in a scheduling application.
- -Programmed in Python using Pandas to manipulate the data and CPLEX to model and solve the optimization problem.
- Researched deep learning and reinforcement learning to create a novel scheduling algorithm.

#### Altera Corp. (now Intel PSG), San Jose, CA Software/Hardware Engineer Intern

2014-2015

- -Maintained and improved internal test infrastructure.
- -Regularly coded Perl firmware and Django web applications. Automated the deployment of infrastructure using Puppet.
- -Modernized the test infrastructure by upgrading the OS and refactoring code to utilize the latest stable release of various software packages.

### Queen's University, Kingston, ON Relevant Coursework

2011-2016

- —Design project titled "Region Tracking in a Sequence of Images". Applied calculus of variations in order to achieve this. Developed an application that successfully tracked the hand of a user from a webcam video and the outline of a bone throughout an MRI scan.
- —Course project titled "Applying Q-Learning to Flappy Bird". Achieved human-level performance by applying a reinforcement learning algorithm to the game Flappy Bird. Simulated the game and coded the algorithm in MATLAB.